Gurdon Montague Butler papers, 1916-1939
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Gurdon Montague Butler papers, 1916-1939
AZ 523
Butler, G. M. (Gurdon Montague), b. 1881
Typescript (carbon) and holograph, personal and professional correspondence. Includes correspondence related to the College of Mines and Engineering (1917-1939), private consulting (1916-1932), and regarding support of University President Cloyd Marvin (1923-1928). Also includes correspondence with family and friends, with civic organizations such as the Masons (1923-1932), the Rotary Club (1921-1933), and with the Tucson Zoning and Planning Commission (1927-1929).
1.3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Dean of the College of Mines and Engineering (1915-1940); Dean of Engineering (1940-1951); director of Arizona Bureau of Mines (1918-1940) at The University of Arizona.
Scope and Content Note
Typescript (carbon) and holograph, personal and professional correspondence. Includes correspondence related to the College of Mines and Engineering (1917-1939), private consulting (1916-1932), and regarding support of University President Cloyd Marvin (1923-1928). Also includes correspondence with family and friends, with civic organizations such as the Masons (1923-1932), the Rotary Club (1921-1933), and with the Tucson Zoning and Planning Commission (1927-1929).
Marvin, Cloyd Heck, 1889-1969; University of Arizona. College of Engineering and Mines -- History; University of Arizona -- History; University of Arizona -- Faculty; Rotary Club (Tucson, Ariz.); Tucson (Ariz.). Planning and Zoning Commission -- Records and correspondence; Freemasons. Arizona -- History
Container List
- University correspondence, College of Mines. 1917-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Equipment requests for Mining and Engineering College. 1917-1918, 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- University correspondence Re: Mining and Metallurgy Mineral Display. 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- University correspondence Re: Engineering Students and the Draft., 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- University correspondence Re: recruiting High School Students to the College of Engineering. 1917-1918, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- University correspondence Re: recommendations for Reserve status. 1917-1918, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- University correspondence Re: "Special course work". 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- University correspondence Re: "Miners Short Course". 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- University correspondence with the Arizona Bureau of Mines. 1917-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous university correspondence. 1917-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- University correspondence relating to Dr. Marvin. 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence with family. 1923-1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Personal correspondence Re: Schools for Gurdon Butler, Jr. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Personal corresepondence with Gus Atchley. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Personal corresepondence Re: Memberships in Mining and Engineering Societies. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Persoal correspondence with the Colorado School of Mines. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Personal correspondence with the Michigan College of Mines. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Personal correspondence Re: Automobiles. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Personal correspondence Re: houses and property. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Personal correspondence Re: goods purchased. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Consulting. 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Personal correspondence with Masons. 1923-1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Personal correspondence and materials Re: Tucson Zoining and Planning Commission. 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous personal correspondence. 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous personal correspondence. 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1926 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1927 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1928 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1931 (January - April) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1931 (May - October) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1932 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". 1933 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Personal correspondence, "Rotary". No Date (Box 3, Folder 11)